
{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What is the capital of Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["Honolulu", "Hilo", "Kona", "Lahaina"],
            "answer": "Honolulu"
        },

        {
            "question": "What is the name of the active volcano on the Big Island of Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["Mauna Kea", "Mauna Loa", "Kilauea", "Haleakala"],
            "answer": "Kilauea"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the famous beach on the North Shore of Oahu?",
            "choices": ["Waikiki", "Lanikai", "Waimea Bay", "Hanauma Bay"],
            "answer": "Waimea Bay"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian dish made with raw fish?",
            "choices": ["Poke", "Lomi Lomi Salmon", "Kalua Pig", "Laulau"],
            "answer": "Poke"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian goddess of fire and volcanoes?",
            "choices": ["Pele", "Hi'iaka", "Laka", "Kapo"],
            "answer": "Pele"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian king who united the islands?",
            "choices": ["Kalakaua", "Kamehameha", "Lunalilo", "Kamehameha II"],
            "answer": "Kamehameha"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian flower necklace?",
            "choices": ["Haku", "Lei", "Kukui", "Maile"],
            "answer": "Lei"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian instrument made from a gourd?",
            "choices": ["Steel Guitar", "Ukulele", "Slack Key Guitar", "Ipu Heke"],
            "answer": "Ukulele"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for hello?",
            "choices": ["Mahalo", "Aloha", "Ohana", "Ono"],
            "answer": "Aloha"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for goodbye?",
            "choices": ["Mahalo", "Ohana", "Aloha", "Ono"],
            "answer": "Aloha"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for thank you?",
            "choices": ["Aloha", "Ohana", "Ono", "Mahalo"],
            "answer": "Mahalo"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for family?",
            "choices": ["Mahalo", "Ohana", "Aloha", "Ono"],
            "answer": "Ohana"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for delicious?",
            "choices": ["Mahalo", "Ohana", "Aloha", "Ono"],
            "answer": "Ono"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for love?",
            "choices": ["Mahalo", "Ohana", "Aloha", "Ono"],
            "answer": "Aloha"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for ocean?",
            "choices": ["Kai", "Wai", "Anuenue", "Honu"],
            "answer": "Kai"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for mountain?",
            "choices": ["Kai", "Wai", "Anuenue", "Mauna"],
            "answer": "Mauna"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for water?",
            "choices": ["Kai", "Wai", "Anuenue", "Honu"],
            "answer": "Wai"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for rainbow?",
            "choices": ["Kai", "Wai", "Anuenue", "Honu"],
            "answer": "Anuenue"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for turtle?",
            "choices": ["Kai", "Wai", "Anuenue", "Honu"],
            "answer": "Honu"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for shark?",
            "choices": ["Pua", "I'a", "Mano", "Hoku"],
            "answer": "Mano"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for fish?",
            "choices": ["Pua", "Hoku", "Mano", "I'a"],
            "answer": "I'a"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for flower?",
            "choices": ["I'a", "Hoku", "Mano", "Pua"],
            "answer": "Pua"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for star?",
            "choices": ["I'a", "Pua", "Mano", "Hoku"],
            "answer": "Hoku"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for sun?",
            "choices": ["I'a", "Hoku", "La", "Hoku"],
            "answer": "La"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for moon?",
            "choices": ["Aloha", "Makani", "La", "Mahina"],
            "answer": "Mahina"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for wind?",
            "choices": ["Mauka", "Mahina", "Makani", "Makai"],
            "answer": "Makani"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Hawaiian word for rain?",
            "choices": ["Mauka", "Waiwai", "Makani", "Ua"],
            "answer": "Ua"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest town on the Big Island?",
            "choices": ["Kona", "Hilo", "Waimea", "Pahoa"],
            "answer": "Hilo"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the town on the Big Island where the Kona coffee is grown?",
            "choices": ["Hilo", "Waimea", "Kona", "Pahoa"],
            "answer": "Kona"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the town in between Kona and Hilo on the Big Island? (Arel lives here)",
            "choices": ["Waimea", "Pahoa", "Honokaa", "Kealakekua"],
            "answer": "Waimea"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the tallest mountain in the world? (It's in Hawaii)",
            "choices": ["Mount Everest", "Mauna Loa", "Mauna Kea", "Kilauea"],
            "answer": "Mauna Kea"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many freeways are there on the Big Island?",
            "choices": ["One", "Two", "Three", "Zero"],
            "answer": "Zero"
        },
        {
            "question": "What year did Hawaii become a state?",
            "choices": ["1959", "1898", "1778", "500"],
            "answer": "1959"
        },
        {
            "question": "What year did Hawaii become a US territory?",
            "choices": ["1959", "1898", "1778", "500"],
            "answer": "1898"
        },
        {
            "question": "What year did Captain Cook discover Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["1959", "1898", "1778", "500"],
            "answer": "1778"
        },
        {
            "question": "What year did the first Polynesians arrive in Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["1959", "1898", "1778", "500"],
            "answer": "500"
        },
        {
            "question": "What year did the first Hawaiians arrive in Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["1400", "300", "800", "500"],
            "answer": "300"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the last Hawaiian monarch?",
            "choices": ["King Kamehameha", "Queen Liliuokalani", "King Kalakaua", "King Kamehameha II"],
            "answer": "Queen Liliuokalani"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest island in Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["Oahu", "Maui", "Kauai", "Big Island"],
            "answer": "Big Island"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the second largest island in Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["Oahu", "Maui", "Kauai", "Big Island"],
            "answer": "Maui"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the third largest island in Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["Oahu", "Maui", "Kauai", "Big Island"],
            "answer": "Oahu"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the smallest island in Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["Kahoolawe", "Niihau", "Lanai", "Big Island"],
            "answer": "Kahoolawe"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the island in Hawaii where the state capital is located?",
            "choices": ["Maui", "Oahu", "Kauai", "Big Island"],
            "answer": "Oahu"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the island in Hawaii where the famous road to Hana is located?",
            "choices": ["Maui", "Oahu", "Kauai", "Big Island"],
            "answer": "Maui"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the island in Hawaii where the famous Waikiki beach is located?",
            "choices": ["Maui", "Kauai", "Oahu", "Big Island"],
            "answer": "Oahu"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the island in Hawaii where the famous lava flows are located?",
            "choices": ["Maui", "Kauai", "Oahu", "Big Island"],
            "answer": "Big Island"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the island in Hawaii where the famous leper colony is located?",
            "choices": ["Maui", "Kauai", "Oahu", "Molokai"],
            "answer": "Molokai"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the island in Hawaii where the famous Napali coast is located?",
            "choices": ["Maui", "Kauai", "Oahu", "Big Island"],
            "answer": "Kauai"
        },
        {
            "question": "On what battleship does the Pearl Harbor memorial sit?",
            "choices": ["USS Missouri", "USS Arizona", "USS Oklahoma", "USS California"],
            "answer": "USS Arizona"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the royal palace in Honolulu?",
            "choices": ["Iolani Palace", "Queen's Palace", "King's Palace", "Prince's Palace"],
            "answer": "Iolani Palace"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the school located in Honolulu that former President Obama attended?",
            "choices": ["Kamehameha", "Iolani", "Punahou", "Mid-Pacific"],
            "answer": "Punahou"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the school located in Waimea that Arel attended?",
            "choices": ["Kamehameha", "Iolani", "Punahou", "Hawaii Preparatory Academy"],
            "answer": "Hawaii Preparatory Academy"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the mascot of the University of Hawaii at Manoa?",
            "choices": ["Rainbow Warriors", "Vulcans", "Rainbows", "Warriors"],
            "answer": "Rainbow Warriors"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the mascot of the University of Hawaii at Hilo?",
            "choices": ["Vikings", "Warriors", "Vulcans", "Sharks"],
            "answer": "Vulcans"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many islands are in Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["8", "6", "4", "10"],
            "answer": "8"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the island in Hawaii where the famous pineapple is grown?",
            "choices": ["Maui", "Oahu", "Kauai", "Lanai"],
            "answer": "Oahu"
        },
        {
            "question": "How do you say 'Merry Christmas' in Hawaiian?",
            "choices": ["Hau'oli La Hanau", "Hau'oli Makahiki Hou", "Mele Kalikimaka", "Aloha Au Ia 'Oe"],
            "answer": "Mele Kalikimaka"
        },
        {
            "question": "How do you say 'Happy New Year' in Hawaiian?",
            "choices": ["Hau'oli La Hanau", "Hau'oli Makahiki Hou", "Mele Kalikimaka", "Aloha Au Ia 'Oe"],
            "answer": "Hau'oli Makahiki Hou"
        },
        {
            "question": "How do you say 'Happy Birthday' in Hawaiian?",
            "choices": ["Hau'oli Makahiki Hou", "Mele Kalikimaka", "Hau'oli La Hanau", "Aloha Au Ia 'Oe"],
            "answer": "Hau'oli La Hanau"
        },
        {
            "question": "How do you say 'I love you' in Hawaiian?",
            "choices": ["Hau'oli Makahiki Hou", "Mele Kalikimaka", "Hau'oli La Hanau", "Aloha Au Ia 'Oe"],
            "answer": "Aloha Au Ia 'Oe"
        },
        {
            "question": "How do you say 'perseverance' in Hawaiian?",
            "choices": ["Kuleana", "Ho'omau", "Laulima", "Malama"],
            "answer": "Ho'omau"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the famous Hawaiian surfer who popularized surfing in the 1950s?",
            "choices": ["Eddie Aikau", "Duke Kahanamoku", "Laird Hamilton", "Bethany Hamilton"],
            "answer": "Duke Kahanamoku"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the most famous Hawaiian baseball player? (According to Wikipedia)",
            "choices": ["Shane Victorino", "Kolten Wong", "Kurt Suzuki", "Brandon League"],
            "answer": "Shane Victorino"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the most famous Hawaiian football player? (According to Wikipedia)",
            "choices": ["Marcus Mariota", "Tua Tagovailoa", "Manti Te'o", "Max Unger"],
            "answer": "Marcus Mariota"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the president in office that refused to annex Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["Theodore Roosevelt", "William McKinley", "Grover Cleveland", "William Taft"],
            "answer": "Grover Cleveland"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the president in office that annexed Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["Theodore Roosevelt", "William McKinley", "Grover Cleveland", "William Taft"],
            "answer": "William McKinley"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the president in office when Hawaii became a state?",
            "choices": ["Dwight Eisenhower", "John F. Kennedy", "Lyndon B. Johnson", "Richard Nixon"],
            "answer": "Dwight Eisenhower"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Hawaiian word for responsibility?",
            "choices": ["Kuleana", "Ho'omau", "Laulima", "Malama"],
            "answer": "Kuleana"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Hawaiian game that is similar to chess?",
            "choices": ["Ulu Maika", "Hula", "Konane", "Makahiki"],
            "answer": "Konane"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which 2002 Disney animated film was set in Hawaii?",
            "choices": ["Moana", "Lilo & Stitch", "The Lion King", "Mulan"],
            "answer": "Lilo & Stitch"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the famous Hawaiian dessert made with ice and flavored syrup, and frequently topped with things such as li hing powder, mochi, and adzuki beans?",
            "choices": ["Snow Cone", "Ice Cream", "Shave Ice", "Sorbet"],
            "answer": "Shave Ice"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the famous Hawaiian dish made with spam and rice?",
            "choices": ["Poke", "Lomi Lomi Salmon", "Kalua Pig", "Spam Musubi"],
            "answer": "Spam Musubi"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the famous Hawaiian dish made with pork and cooked in an underground oven?",
            "choices": ["Poke", "Lomi Lomi Salmon", "Kalua Pig", "Laulau"],
            "answer": "Kalua Pig"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the famous Hawaiian dessert made with fried sweet bread and fruit / cream filling?",
            "choices": ["Malasada", "Ice Cream", "Shave Ice", "Sorbet"],
            "answer": "Malasada"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the traditional Hawaiian feast that is often accompanied by live music, hula dancing, and a pig cooked in the ground?",
            "choices": ["Luau", "Makahiki", "Ho'olaule'a", "Paniolo"],
            "answer": "Luau"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the famous beach on the Big Island that is known for its black sand and sea turtles?",
            "choices": ["Waikiki", "Lanikai", "Waimea Bay", "Punalu'u"],
            "answer": "Punalu'u"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the famous beach on the Big Island that is known for its green sand?",
            "choices": ["Waikiki", "Papakolea", "Waimea Bay", "Punalu'u"],
            "answer": "Papakolea"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the famous waterfall on the Big Island that is known for its 442-foot drop?",
            "choices": ["Akaka Falls", "Rainbow Falls", "Hi'ilawe Falls", "Wai'ale Falls"],
            "answer": "Akaka Falls"
        }

    ]
}